Guide to the Center for International Studies records, 1960-1983.
Center for International Studies records
- Series XV. Research, Articles, and Presentations
  - Articles Concerning India
    - "Energetics of Indian Cattle in Their Environment," by Stewart Odend'hal, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - "The Flow of Energy in an Agricultural Society," by Ray A. Rappapart, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - "The Sacred Cows of India" (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - A Jajmani System of North India: Its structure, Magnitude, and Meaning," by Harold A. Gould (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - "The Cultural Ecology of India's Sacred Cattle," by Marvin Harris (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Articles Concerning Agriculture
    - The Subsistence Farmer in Traditional Economies," by John W, Miller (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - "Policies for Broadening the Desirable Income Effects of Rapid Growth in Agricultural Production," by John W. Mellor (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - "Agricultural Extension in a Kumaonese Village," by R.D. Sanwall (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - "Agricultural Extension in a Kumaonese Village," by R.D. Sanwall, Version II (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - "The Ability of the Developing Countries to Meet Their Own Agricultural Needs in the 1980s," by Joseph W. Willett, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - "Intervention for Institutional Change: A Strategy of Multiple Goals", October 23, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 108)
  - Cross Cultural Research in Institutional Development, A Two Year Report", July 1964-June 1966 (Box 2, Folder 109)
  - OECD: Agenda Item VI-Promotion and Organization of Fundamental Research, March 1968 (Box 2, Folder 110)
  - Evolution of the IEP-Cornell Organization Strategy", November 1970 (Box 2, Folder 111)
  - "A Perspective View of Self-Management in a Socialist Context", 1970 (Box 2, Folder 112)
  - Various Papers on Economic Issues, 1970-1973 (Box 2, Folder 113)
  - "Another Chance to Help Save the World-Changing the Present US Policy on the Proposed UN University", October 3, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 114)
  - Information on the Volunteer Speakers Service of the US Information Agency", November 24, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 115)
  - Society for International Studies Papers, January 1974-March 1975 (Box 2, Folder 116)
  - Papers on the Environment, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 117)
  - Race and Class in Latin America: Columbia University Press, 1968-1979 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - "A Survey of Intensive Programs in the Uncommon Languages," by Roy Andrew Miller, Summer 1964 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - "Water Resources Research Program Under the Water Resources Research Act of 1964: A Report to the Chairman Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs, U.S. Congress" - From Cornell University Water Resources Center, August 1965 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Article Criticising Michigan State and Reactions, Spring 1966 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - "The Role of the U.S. Professor in Developing Countries," by William Foote Whyte, August 29, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - "The Role and Responsibility of the Student in Higher Education in Sweden, and Related Notes, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - "Internationalism in Eclipse: THE ICFTU After Two Decades," by John P. Windmuller, February 23, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Assorted Brochures for Global Food Concerns, 1970s (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - "Comparative Studies of Sub-National Social Systems," Draft Statement (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - "Comparative Tropical Food Economics," A Proposal Submitted to the Committee on Structural Change by Professor Thomas Poleman (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - "Trustees Preliminary Statement: A Confidential Assessment of Cornell's Immediate Needs and Opportunities on Behalf of its Centennial Program" (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - "Water Management in the Czechoslovak Socialist Republic," By Dr. Vladimir Reinhardt and Ing. Vaclav Vucka (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - PACT (Private Agencies Collaborating Together, INC) Explanatory Guide (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - "Organization and Procedures of the Materials Science Center," Revised January 1, 1968, January 1, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - "Chapter 1 - Plural Studies: Perspectives and Problems," in "Pluralism in Africa", 1969 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - "Risk is the Peasant's Lot,"by Maurice Linkin1, January 1971 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - "Public Authority in a Developing Political Community: the Case of India" (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - "The Management of Communal Conflict," by Milton J. Esman (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - "International Interests of Cornell University," by Lauriston Sharp (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - "Peru: the Master is Dead," from "Dissent", June 1971 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - "Race, Culture, and Social Structure in the Peruvian Andes," by William W. Stein, June 20, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Introduction from "Aymara Communities and the Bolivian Agrarian Reform," by William Carter (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - "Maximizing in Jaymaniland: A Model of Caste Relations," by Martin Orans, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - "American Anthropologist," Appendix, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - "Ritual Regulation of Environmental Relations Among a New Guinea People," by Ray A. Rappaport (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - "Eating Christmas in the Kalahari," by Richard Borshay Lee, from "Natural History, December 1969 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - "Why a World Food Conference?" by Daniel E. Shaughnessy, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - "The Future of Interdisciplinary Problem-Oriented Courses for Undergraduate in International and Comparative Studies, March 3, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - "The Re-Entry Crisis," by Richard B Stolley, Life Magazine, March 19, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - "American Academic Ethnics and Social Research Abroad: The Lesson of Project Camelot, by Kalman H. Silvert, July 1965 (Box 10, Folder 61)
  - Papers Related to Iran, 1974-1975 (Box 17, Folder 35)
  - "Sex Roles and Fertility of College Women: A Follow Up", February 21, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 36)
  - Papers Concerning Closure of Ithaca Food, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 37)
  - "Socio-Economic Change and Fertility in Costa Rica", 1976 (Box 17, Folder 39)
  - "Package of Instructional Social Surveys of North Carolina", October 15, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Presentation on "Institution Building for Rural Development" for IICA Staff in Costa Rica, January 3-9, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Presentation on "Watergate and U.S. Foreign Policy" for Cleveland Alumni Association, September 12, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Notes for Speech on "Problems of Professional Staffing of Legislations in Comparative Perspective," at ASPA Confernece, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Notes from Speech on "The Future of Public Administration in the U.S.", April 26, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Presentation on the Meaning of Detente for the Cincinnati Alumni Club, May 10, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - MSU - IB - Agricultural Workshop Institute: Institution - Client Relations in Third World Rural Development, August 12, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Papers on Milton J. Esman's Presentation to Trustee Council, October 1974 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Papers on "Morality in Foreign Policy" Presentation for Lackawanna Cornell Club, February 4, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - "The Perils and Rewards of Interdisciplinary Teaching," Speech at Ithaca college, April 10, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - PPSTDN Summer Institute, July 19, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Papers for Cause on Southeast Asia (August 9-20, 1976) at the Center for Area and Culture Studies, Summer 1976 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Assorted Outlines for Conferences on International Affairs, Fall 1976 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - "Scottish Nationalism, North Sea Oil and the British Response" (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Speech on the PPBS System and the Evolution of Public Budgeting (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Presentation at the World Bank on IBRD-DFC Presentation on Institution Building and Developing Banks (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Presentation on "The Political Utility of Equalitarian Ideologies in Developing Countries (Box 18, Folder 31)
- Series XVI. Peace Studies
  - Peace Studies Papers, March-May 1973 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Peace Studies Papers, June-August 1973 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Peace Studies Papers, September-November 1973 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Peace Studies Fellowship Program, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Peace Studies Program Monthly Financial Statement, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Peace Studies Papers, June-August 1972 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Peace Studies Papers, September-November 1972 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - PSP Proposals: Ford Grants, 1971-1973 (Box 15, Folder 50)
  - PSP Visitors Correspondence: Milt Lutenberg, 1974-1976 (Box 15, Folder 51)
  - PSP Proposals: Re D Long/Reppy, 1975-1976 (Box 15, Folder 52)
  - PSP Seminars (Box 15, Folder 53)
  - PSP Steering Committee (Box 15, Folder 54)
  - PSP Conference Sheffer-Leitenberg (Box 15, Folder 55)
  - PSP Staff/Visitors, 1973-1976 (Box 15, Folder 58)
  - Peace Studies Program, September-November 1970 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Peace Studies Program, December 1970-February 1971 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Peace Studies Program, March 1971 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Peace Studies Program, April 1971 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Peace Studies Program, May-June 1971 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Peace Studies Program, July-August 1971 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Peace Studies Program, September-November 1971 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Peace Studies Program, December 1971-February 1972 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Peace Studies Program, March-May 1972 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Peace Studies Program, December 1972-February 1973 (Box 16, Folder 10)
- Series XVII. Western Societies Program
  - Papers for Publication
    - "A Conceptual Framework for the Study of Clientelism," by Luigi Graziano, Draft, April 1975 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - "Fertility and Occupation; Coal Mining Populations in the Nineteenth and Early Twentieth Centuries in Europe and America", July 1975 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - "From Center to Periphery: Alternate Models of National-Local Policy Impact and an Application to France and Italy, by Sidney Tarrow, April 1976 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - "From Center to Periphery: Alternate Models of National-Local Policy Impact and an Application to France and Italy, by Sidney Tarrow, Draft, April 1976 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - "The Limits of Consensus: the Reorganization of British Local Government and the French Contrast," by Douglas Ashford, July 1976 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - "Patronage and its Opponents: A Theory and Some European Cases," by Martin Shefter of Cornell University, May 1977 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - "The Limits of Consensus: the Reorganization of British Local Government and the French Contrast," by Douglas Ashford, Draft, July 1976 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Clark - Occ. Paper (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - AIKEN/DEPRE OCC Paper (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - "A Conceptual Framework for the Study of Clientelism," by Luigi Graziano (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Further Drafts for the Graziano Paper (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - "A Conceptual Framework for the Study of Clientelism," by Luigi Graziano (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Sidney Tarrow
    - Grant Applications, S. Tarrow, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - Project Report Proposal: Regionalism, Ethnicity, and Part. In Contemp. Europe..., September 12, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - S. Tarrow Correspondence, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - Sidney Tarrow Papers and Applications, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - S. Tarrow Correspondence, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 35)
    - WSP Visitors and Other Depts. Sid Tarrow., 1974-1975 (Box 16, Folder 36)
    - S. Tarrow Correspondence, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 37)
    - WSP-Steering Comm. (Exec. - S. Tarrow), mid 1970s (Box 16, Folder 39)
  - WSP Proposals Depository, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - WSP Proposals Clark Fund, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - WSP Seminar Papers, September 1973-April 1974 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - WSP Proposals: Ford/Rockefeller Migrants in Europe and North America, 1973-1975 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Western Societies Program, Fellowships, Conferences, and Study Abroad, November 4, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - WSP Proposals, Ashford, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence about Western Societies Seminars, 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - WSP Proposal Ford, Common Problems, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - WSP Proposals: Research Planning Group, August 1975 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Western Societies Program Papers and Sept. Memo, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Western Societies Program, September-November 1975 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Western Societies Program Seminars, 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Western Societies Program Memoranda, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - WSP Migrant Political Organization, October-November, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - WSP German Fund, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Western Societies Program Papers, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - WSP Proposals: Seminar on European Studies (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - WSP Mailing Labels (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - WSP Occasional Papers, Financial (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - WSP Columbia Conference, 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Western Societies Program Papers and Correspondence, mid 1970s (Box 16, Folder 38)
  - WSP Conference. Modes of Participation, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 40)
  - WSP: Staff/Visitors, June-September 1975 (Box 16, Folder 41)
  - Visitors' Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 16, Folder 42)
  - WSP Seminars, 1975-1976 (Box 16, Folder 43)
  - Assorted Western Studies Program Papers and Documents, mid 1970s, mid 1970s (Box 16, Folder 44)
  - A. Milnor's Paper and Comments, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - "Reflection on Violence in Northern Ireland" by A. Milnor, and Comments, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - "Politics, Violence, and Social Change in Northern Ireland," by Andrew Milnor, June 1976 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Milnor-Occ. Paper Reactions, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Milnor Paper (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - A.J. Milnor, "Some Reflections on Violence in Northern Ireland" (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - A. Milnor, "Reflections on Violence in Northern Ireland" (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Title IV Application - WSP, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 9)
- Series XVIII. Overarching CIS Chronology
  - Book of CIS Chronology Papers, August 1, 1980-September 30, 1980 (Box 5)
  - Book of CIS Chronology Papers, October 1, 1980-November 28, 1980 (Box 5)
  - Book of CIS Chronology Papers, December 1, 1980-January 30, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Book of CIS Chronology Papers, February 2, 1981-March 31, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Book of CIS Chronology Papers, April-May 1981 (Box 5)
  - Book of CIS Chronology Papers, June 1, 1981-July 31, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Book of CIS Chronology Papers, August 3-September 30, 1981 (Box 5)
- Series XIX. Agricultural Institutes
  - "Progress Report from the Committee on the Role of the College of Agriculture in International Agricultural Development, June 1961 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence Concerning the Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences, 1964-1977 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Relationship Between International Agriculture Development and Ford Foundation, 1965-1969 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Relationship Between the International Agriculture Department and the Ford Foundation, 1965-1972 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Various Papers Faculty and Staff of International Agriculture Department, 1965-1973 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - "A Projection of the International Agricultural Program Sponsored by the College of Agriculture, Cornell University: A Request for Partial Funding Through the International Education Act of 1966", May 1, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Papers for Cornell's International Agricultural Program, 1966-1977 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - International Agricultural Development Advisory Committee Meeting, September 28, 1967-June 6, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - "A Programme of Collaboration: Faculty of Agriculture, Forestry, and Veterinary Sciences, University of Ibadan and College of Agriculture, University of Cornell," by K.L. Turk, December 1970 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - International Agricultural Development Visitors, 1970s (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - "Report of the Committee on International Programs of the New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences, Cornell University", May 15, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - "International Agricultural Development Publications", August 1972 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - International Agriculture's Involvement with Costa Rica, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Summary of International Agriculture Advisory Committee Meeting, March 15, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - "Future Perspectives in International Agriculture at Cornell," by Edwin B. Oyer, September 25, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - "International Agriculture", May 1974 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Drafts of IICA(Inter-American Institute of Agricultural Sciences)-Cornell Agreements, August-December, August-December, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Papers from IICA Events, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Summary of the November 17 Meeting of the Advisory Committee for International Agriculture (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - "World Agriculture: Our Challenge" (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Cornell's Program for International Agriculture (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Assorted Documents of Kenneth L. Turk, Director of International Agricultural Development, August 25, 1969-April 8, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - International Development Budget Review for FY 1969-1970, Submitted March 27, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Ten Year Projection of International Studies: International Agricultural Development, College of Agriculture, Cornell University (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Rural Development Committee Chronology, July 1978-September 1978 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Rural Development Committee Chronology, October 1978-November 1978 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Rural Development Committee Chronology, November 1978-March 30, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Rural Development Committee Chronology, March 30, 1979-June 1, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Rural Development Committee Chronology, May 1979-June 1979 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Series XX. Library Resources for Classes
  - Readings for CIS II - pc1 (Box 17)
  - Readings for CIS II - pc2 (Box 17)
  - Readings for CIS II - pc3 (Box 17)
  - Readings for CIS II - pc4 (Box 17)
  - Readings for CIS III - pc c.1 (Box 17)
  - Readings for CIS III - pc c.2 (Box 17)
  - Readings for CIS III - pc c.3 (Box 17)
  - Readings for CIS III - pc c.4 (Box 17)
  - Kang Chao Agricultural Production in Communist China - pc1 (Box 17)
  - Wolf Peasants - pc1 (Box 17)
  - Tannebaum: The Reach Spirit of Tachai - pc2 (Box 17)
  - Nicholson: Political Aspects of Indian Food Policy - pc c.1 (Box 17)
  - Myers and Snow: Chinese Peasant Economy of Red Star Over China (Box 17)
  - Kang Chao Agricultural Production in Communist China - pc1 (Box 17)
  - Chen: New Earth - pc2 (Box 17)
  - Some Basic Facts About the People's Commune - pc c.1 (Box 17)
  - Class Struggle in Yellow Sandhill Commune - pc1 (Box 17)
- Series XXI. Audio
  - Carpenter Lectures, 1975
    - Cora or Coral Bell, Richard Rosencrance, April 3, May 7, 1975; 53/5/tr.254 #1
    - Alistair Buchan, April 4, 1975; 53/5/tr.254 #2
    - Pierre Hassner, April 14, 1975; 53/5/tr.254 #3
    - Robert Gilpin, Leonard Silk, April 25, 28, 1975; 53/5/tr.254 #4